Guide to the W. Lloyd Wright papers, 1786-1945 MS2075
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Correspondence, 1795-1906; MS2075 Series 1; 2.5 Linear feet
  - Ould, Robert (1820-1882). Letter: Georgetown, DC, to the Secretary of the Navy, Washington, 1855 June 25 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Summary: Writes recommending someone for position of watchman. (Ould was a Washington lawyer and was later Assistant Secretary of War in the Confederacy).
  - Page, Thomas Nelson (1853-1922). Letter: Hartford, Conn., to M.E. Waring, Chautauqua, N.Y., 1892 July 28 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Summary: Aurees to a speaking engagement. (Page was an American author and an ambassador to Italy, 1913-1919).
  - Page, Thomas Nelson (1853-1922). Letter: London, to William Carey, N.Y., 1894 July 10 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Summary: Sends a revised article about his work Marse Chan; is greatly enjoying his tour of England.
  - Page, Thomas Nelson (1853-1922). Letter: 1759 R 09. Washington, DC, to Robert Howard Russell, New York, 1898 March 28 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Summary: Suggests using a manuscript journal he has seen as a basis for a book by Russell.
  - Page, Thomas Nelson (1853-1922). Letter: York Harbor, ME, to Robert H. Russell, NY, 1903 August 21 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Summary: Offers to the North American Review his article on lynching of Negros.
  - Page, Thomas Nelson (1853-1922). Letter: 1759 R 09., to Frank W. Hoyt, Montclair, NJ, 1906 December 04 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Summary: Thanks Hoyt for a sympathetic review for his book of poems, probably The Coast of Bohemia. Defends the use of some of his rhymes.
  - Payne, John Howard (1791-1852). Letter: Washington, to Elizabeth Payne, 1850 August 19 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Summary: Mentions recent violent arguments in the Senate, efforts to see governor Marcy, and visits with his friend Jonathan Meredith. (Payne was an American actor and playwright).
  - Ream, Vinnie (1847-1914). Letter: to unidentified recipient, 18--., undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Summary: Returns some items to the recipient. (Ream was an American sculptor and composer).
  - Riggs, George Washington (1813-1881). Letter: Washington, DC, to W. Stone, Jr., 1861 March 18 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Summary: Encloses a note to which he has earlier referred. (Riggs was a Washington banker and one of the founders of Corcoran and Riggs banking firm).
  - Riggs, George Washington (1813-1881). Letter: Washington, DC, to Joel Munsell, Albany, 1869 October 28 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Summary: Asks to be sent a copy of a Spanish work translated by Buckingham Smith.
  - Roberdeau, Isaac (1763-1829). Letter: Washington, to Thomas Aspinwall, 1823 August 20 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Summary: Sends a letter to Mr. Perkins, who has made improvements in the use of steam power. (Roberdeau was a civil and military engineer and was chief of the Topographical Bureau in Washington).
  - Rog, Charlotte Fiske Bates, (1838-1916). Letter: Washington, DC, to Mrs. Edward Russell Jones, 1902 March 18 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Summary: Encloses her autograph and some others. (Rog was an American author and compiler).
  - Royall, Anne Newport (1769-1854). Letter: Washington, to Messrs. Green & Jarvis, 1828 June 07 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Summary: Thanks Green and Jarvis for advertising her book in their newspaper the United States Telegraph; deplores federal government corruption. (Royall was an American author and publisher).
  - Seaton, William Winston (1785-1866). Letter: to an unidentified recipient, 1849 February 26 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Summary: Will send a carriage to take his friend to the U.S. Senate. (Seaton was a journalist, editor and mayor of Washington, D.C., 1840-1850).
  - Seaton, William Winston (1785-1866). Letter: to "05 good friend", not after 1866, Circa 1865 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Summary: Letter of introduction for an acquaintance.
  - Seawell, Molly Elliot (1860-1916). Letter: Washington, DC, to "Dear Sir", 1907 May 03 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Summary: Mentions her recent short fiction. (Seawell was an American author).
  - Singleton, Otho Robards (1814-1889). Letter: Washington, DC, to Mrs. Linn Boyd, 1875 December 15 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Summary: Describes the current state of social life in Washington and political events in Congress. (Singleton was a U.S. Congressman from Mississippi, 1853-1855, 1857-1861, 1875-1887).
  - Southworth, Emma Dorothy Eliza Nevitte (1819-1899). Letter: Prospect Cottage, 1854 January 08 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Summary: Mentions her own sickness and that of Miss Gordon. (Southworth was an American author).
  - Southworth, Emma Dorothy Eliza Nevitte (1819-1899). Letter: Yonkers, NY, to A.M. Irving, 1878 July 02 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Summary: Sends Irving an autograph.
  - Southworth, Emma Dorothy Eliza Nevitte (1819-1899). Letter: Yonkers, NY, to Harry Watkins, 1889 March 21 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Summary: Praises his book His Worst Enemy. Mentions death of her nephew in a railroad accident and death of her sister Edith.
  - Spofford, Harriet Elizabeth Prescott (1835-1921). Letter: to Mrs. E.R. Jones, 1902 February 07 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Summary: Sends autograph. (Spofford was an American author).
  - Staughton, William (1770-1829). Letter: Georgetown SC, to Dr. Rogers, Philadelphia, 1795 April 25 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Summary: Dislikes Georgetown because of slavery and lack of success in religious endeavors; expects to leave in June. (Staughton was a Baptist clergyman and the first president of Columbian College (now George Washington University), 1822-1829).
  - Stelle, Pontius Delare (b. 1763). Letter: City of Washington, to Jonathan Rhea, Trenton NJ, 1813 October 18 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Summary: Asks Rhea to help him raise money by the first of the next month. Stelle was a Washington hotel keeper and the brother of Rachel De Cow).
  - Stelle, Pontius Delare (b. 1763). Letter: City of Washington, to Jonathan Rhea, Trenton, NJ, 1814 July 22 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Summary: Describes his family's dire financial situation; mentions the approaching British army and preparations in Washington for the city's defense.
  - Stoddert, Benjamin (1751-1813). Letter: Georgetown, to Messrs. Samuel & J. Smith, Baltimore, 1786 March 08 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Summary: Concerns payment drawn on their establishment. (Stoddert was the first Secretary of the Navy, 1798-1801).
  - Stoddert, Benjamin (1751-1813). Letter: Georgetown, to John Templeman, Philadelphia, 1792 October 31 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Summary: Describes a contract he has signed to buy a house in Georgetown,Washington, D.C. The letter indicates at time of sending he had enclosed a copy of the contract. That enclosure is not with this letter.
  - Sykes, George (1802-1880). Letter: Washington, to "Dear Friend", 1846 February 17 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Summary: Mentions possibility that James Buchanan will accept a Supreme Court appointment, praises his actions in the controversy over the northwest border of the United States. (Sykes was a U.S. Representative from New Jersey).
  - Thornton, William (1759-1828). Letter: Patent Office, to Caesar A. Rodney, Wilmington, DE, 1810 June 28 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Summary: Petitions Rodney as Attorney-General, in a humorous poem, to allow more funds for building the Capitol in Washington, D.C. (Thornton was the architect of the U.S. Capitol until 1802 and the Superintendent of Patents, 1802-1828).
  - Thornton, William (1759-1828). Letter: City of Washington, to William Young, 1817 October 30 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Summary: Concerns payment for a shipment of goods.
  - Thornton, William (1759-1828). Letter: to Mr. Leeton, 1818 July 15 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Summary: Concerns a notice that must appear in the paper three times a week for three weeks.
  - Thornton, William (1759-1828). Letter: City of Washington, to Hyde de Neuville, NY, 1819 September 25 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Summary: Concerns some models of brick machines made by Adam Stewart of Philadelphia.
  - United States Commissioners of the City of Washington. Letter: Washington, to George Washington, Mt. Vernon, 1798 October 18 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Summary: Enclosed is an estimate of the cost of houses Washington proposed to build in Washington; Washington later agreed to the terms for building two houses. (Commissioners appointed to lay out the city of Washington were Gustavus Scott, William Thornton and Alexander White).
  - Van Ness, John P. (1770-1846). Letter: Washington, to Y. Eddy, Philadelphia, 1809 October 06 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Summary: Concerns a debt owed to the late W.M. Biddle of Philadelphia. (Van Ness was a U.S. Congressman from New York, 1801-1803, and the mayor of Washington, 1830-1834).
  - Weightman, Roger Chew (1787-1876). Letter: Washington, to M.D. Phillips, Rochester, NY, 1853 May 31 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Summary: States his correct address. (Weightman was Chief clerk of the U.S. patent office, June 1851-May 1853).
  - Weightman, Roger Chew (1787-1876). Letter: Washington, to R.A. Shirer, Georgetown, DC, 1866 February 10 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Summary: Orders some ale.
  - Wirt, William (1772-1834). Letter: Washington, to "Dear Sir", 1821 October 20 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Summary: Note of introduction. (Wirt was the United States Attorney-General, 1817-1829).
  - Wolf, Simon (1836-1923). Letter: Washington, to Adam Badeau, 1869 January 12 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Summary: Invites him to attend the circumcision of his son. (Wolf was a Washington lawyer and author).
  - Wylie, Andrew (1814-1905). Letter: Washington, to John Sherman, 1877 June 06 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Summary: Recommends an appointment to Sherman, Secretary of the Treasury. (Wylie was a judge of the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia, 1863-1885).%32882013824589
- Financial papers, 1796-1869; MS2075 Series 2; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series includes financial papers such as bills, receipts, stock certificates, and checks dealing with banking, business, and transportation. The material covers the years 1796-1943. These papers include bank records from the Bank of Alexandria, Bank of Columbia, and the First National Bank of Washington. These records are from prominent citizens such as Joseph Henry from Corcoran & Riggs, John Mason, and the Metropolitan Police Department.
  - Financial Records--Bank 11 documents, 1796 July 05-1801 February 12 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    including one share of stock in the Bank of Alexandria, dated July 5, 1796 and an exchange for $1000, dated February 12, 1801, to John Mason, the second president of the Bank of Columbia. Also of note is a letter from General Walter Stewart, dated May 25, 1795, to John Templeman, an incorporator and director of the Bank of Columbia, concerning real estate in George Town and Washington.
  - Financial Records--Bonds, Bounties, Certificates and Check 7 documents, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    including an exchange for 115 pounds for Joseph Henry from Corcoran & Riggs to George Peabody & Co. and 4 certificates of land grants, each for 160 acres from the Department of the Interior.
  - Financial Records--Bills and Receipt 24 documents, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    including a receipt of $40 to William Wilson Corcoran, philanthropist, art patron and benefactor to the George Washington University, from John Mason for house rent and a bill for 2500 lbs. of hay sold to the United States Quartermaster General by Richard Bland Lee, statesman and member of the first Congress under the Constitution.
  - Financial Records--Hotel bill 5 documents, 1838 May 07-1864 April 03 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    including a bill from Brown's Indian Queen Hotel, for May 7, 1838, a bill from the National Hotel, for February 11-22, 1835, and a bill from Willards' Hotel, for March 3, 1864.
  - Financial Records--Metropolitan Police Check, 1867 November 14-1869 November 20 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    16 checks from the First National Bank of Washington to the Department of Metropolitan Police, from November 14, 1867, to November 20, 1869.
  - Financial Records--Shipping transportation 9 documents, 1800 December 03-1818 November 23 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    including transportation costs approved December 3, 1800, for taking Capt. Blackburn's company from Norfolk to Dumfries and a notice for a Furs & Peltries Auction on the 23rd of November, 1818, at the warehouses of the Superintendent of Indian Trade, George Town and the District of Columbia. Also includes a letter to the Judges of the Circuit Court of the United States, dated June 10, 1819, from Richard Wallach and John Graeff, appointed commissioners, for making certain turnpike roads in the District of Columbia.
- Miscellaneous, 1794-1945; MS2075 Series 3; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series is composed of invitations, letters, wills, lottery tickets, proclamations, testimonies, DC Social Registers, and auction catalogues. These items range in date from 1794-1945 and concern the Washington lottery, indenture and slavery, newspapers, and Washington real estate. Materials of note include lottery tickets for Federal City lotteries of the late 19th century, and a collection of letters by Mary Clemmer (1839-1884), author and insightful chronicler of Washington life.
  - Miscellaneous--Churche Membership card of Elizabeth Ford to the Methodist Episcopal Church, 1853 September (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous--Invitation 5 documents, 1852-1861 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    including an invitation from W.H. Winder for dinner at Willard's Hotel at 5 o'clock on 11 July 1852 and an invitation to Gideon Welles to be present at the Post Office Department on the occasion of raising a flag over the building, dated May 18, 1861.
  - Miscellaneous--Legal Records--Wills, appeal 6 documents, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    including several wills and military discharge papers.
  - Miscellaneous--Letters from Civil War 8 documents, including general orders, requests for rations, ammunition and troops., undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous--Letters of Phillip Barton Key and possible duel 4 documents, 1843 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    including letters from Philip Barton Key and Captain C.A. May, as well as letters from mutual friends, J.M. Carlisle and John P. McLoughlin, who through their diplomacy prevented a duel between Barton and May. All dated in 1843.
  - Miscellaneous--Letters of Mary Clemmer Collection of 56 autograph letters signed, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    An exceedingly interesting correspondence--refreshingly eloquent in praise of friends and in blame of foes. Miss Clemmer (Mary Clemmer Ames in the earlier letters) was widely known for her Washington correspondence, in which men and measures were discussed without fear or favor, in leading journals of the period.
  - Miscellaneous--Letters to W. Lloyd Wright 23 documents, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    including invitations, letters of thanks for donations and certificates of membership and correspondence from the various societies to which Mr. Wright belonged, such as the Washington Society of Engineers, the Columbia Historical Society and the Society of Natives of the District of Columbia.
  - Miscellaneous--Lotterie 7 documents, 1794 January 15 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    including several tickets for Federal City Lotteries, a right to three shares in the hotel lottery, 15 January 1794, and records of meetings of the Managers of the Federal City Lottery.
  - Miscellaneous--Newspaper 4 documents, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    including a receipt and a supplement for the United States Telegraph.
  - Miscellaneous--Proclamation Proclamation of peace issued by Mayor James A. Blake, 1815 February 18 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    announcing the end of the War of 1812.
  - Miscellaneous--Real Estate 17 documents, 1830 September 20-1855 April 30 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    including an indenture signed by John P. Van Ness, Mayor of Washington, on September 20, 1830 and a letter from W.H. Winder offering to sell the National Theatre for $55,000, dated March 30, 1855.
  - Miscellaneous--Slavery 2 documents, 1859 April 29 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    including a notice of emancipation for Jacob Pendall, dated April 29, 1859.
  - Miscellaneous--Testimonial 4 documents, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    including a petition to the President of the United States for the appointment of Benjamin B. French to the post of Marshal of the District of Columbia and a testimonial for the acceptance of an application for a clerkship in one of the executive departments.
  - Miscellaneous--Auction catalogue, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Auction catalogue for an exhibition and sale of items from the libraries of W. Lloyd Wright after his death, by order of his sister, as well as Florence H. Crane and others.
  - Miscellaneous Bookplate, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    2 bookplate stamps and several bookplates of W. Lloyd Wright.
  - Americana and Early Documents of Congress Catalogue No. 18, undated; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Select Americana with an Addendum of U.S. and Mexican Constitutions Catalogue No. 21, undated; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Directory: complete listing of 18869 appointive positions in the District of Columbia, Circa 1933; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Social Register Summer 1934 Washington DC portion, Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Social Register Summer 1935 Washington DC portion, Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Social Register Summer 1939 Washington DC portion, Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Social Register Summer 1940 Washington DC portion, Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Social Register Summer 1944 Washington DC portion, Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Social Register Summer 1945 Washington DC portion, Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Folger Shakespeare Library, 1932-1933; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 10)